<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>router on Nerd things and more...</title>
    <link>https://earvingad.github.io/tags/router/</link>
    <description>Recent content in router on Nerd things and more...</description>
    <image>
      <title>Nerd things and more...</title>
      <url>https://earvingad.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://earvingad.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 13:23:58 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://earvingad.github.io/tags/router/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AdGuardHome, like Pi-hole but...better(?)</title>
      <link>https://earvingad.github.io/posts/adguardhome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 13:23:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://earvingad.github.io/posts/adguardhome/</guid>
      <description>AdGuard Home is a…
Privacy protection center for you and your devices
Free and open source, powerful network-wide ads &amp;amp; trackers blocking DNS server.
It has a windows, Mac, Android and iOS app. Also a web extension, it is also offering a DNS service, VPN service and a package for OpenWrt. We will focus on the latter, I wrote briefly about it the Ad Blocking, simple &amp;amp; fast entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWrt or How to give your router steroids</title>
      <link>https://earvingad.github.io/posts/openwrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:14:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://earvingad.github.io/posts/openwrt/</guid>
      <description>The OpenWrt Project is a Linux operating system targeting embedded devices. Instead of trying to create a single, static firmware, OpenWrt provides a fully writable filesystem with package management. This frees you from the application selection and configuration provided by the vendor and allows you to customize the device through the use of packages to suit any application(…)
Yeeeah baby! good soup!
Have you ever hated your wireless router so much that you wanted to smash it to the wall because it is just a piece of useless shit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Blocking, simple &amp; fast</title>
      <link>https://earvingad.github.io/posts/adblocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 21:24:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://earvingad.github.io/posts/adblocking/</guid>
      <description>We all hate ads.
According to Wikipedia,
Ad blocking or ad filtering is a software capability for blocking or altering online advertising in a web browser, an application or a network. This may be done using browser extensions or other methods.
So you have choices
I am not going to detail but give the practical and useful information about the fastest and easiest way to block ads
Browser extensions You need, always, no matter what, a web browser ad block extension.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
